MAJ (DR) ABHISHEK SINGH RATHORE

109, AWHO Colony, Ambabari, Jaipur – 302039 E-mail: dr.abhishek.singh78@gmail.com

Cell: +917014630637

Professional Summary

A highly personable, competent, disciplined, confident and team spirited doctor recognized for excelling in varied culturally diverse and evolving social fabric of the millennial India.

As I have served a wide cohort of the Indian army. I also have the privilege of serving the district that produces the maximum number of soldiers in service and veterans of the Indian army.

The wide range of experience that put strenuous demands and shaped me as a clinician in aspects of social justice, poverty syndromes, social insurance, public health, overpopulation, education, violence. I now seek an opportunity to help people by applying my skills and knowledge.

The ongoing COVID 19 PANDEMIC is a reflection of human resilience, intelligence and ignorance. Mother nature can be very cruel and humbling. This entire period has made me look back and realize that only regularized and quality conscious institutions (military institutions, monasteries, academic institutions) with true leadership will survive the after math.

Core Qualifications

- Very caring and compassionate with a strong desire to help people and make a difference
- Experience with clients of all ages backgrounds and conditions
- Profound knowledge of diabetic disorders and conditions and their treatments
- Great communication and writing skills needed in drafting and giving reports
- Ability to work with a team of doctors
- Understanding of all types of assessments and testing

Areas of Expertise

.

- Preventive care expert
- Patient Care
- Immunization
- Patient Emotional Support
- Wound Treatment
- Patient Advice
- Mentoring Nurses
- Family Practice Professional
- Quality Assurance Awareness
- Strategic Planning Expertise
- Excellent Listener
- · Business-minded Practice
- Honest Medical Professional
- Forthcoming with Information
- Empathetic and Courteous

Professional Work History

• MO-I/C (WEST ZONE DOCTOR)

Reliance Industries Ltd.

Jun 2020 - Apr 2021

Udaipur, Rajasthan

• Medical Officer Apr 2018 – Oct 2019
JK Cement Works Nimbahera, Rajasthan

• Medical Officer Dec 2016 - Mar 2018 ECHS – Ex-Serviceman Contributory Health Scheme Dausa, Rajasthan

• Medical Officer Mar 2013 to Dec 2016 ECHS – Ex-Serviceman Contributory Health Scheme Chirawa, Rajasthan

• Junior Resident Medical ICU
FORTIS Escorts Hospital

Jan 2012 to Mar 2013
Jaipur, Rajasthan

Medical Officer
 Indian Armed Forces
 (IN THE ACTING RANKS AS CAPT AND MAJOR INDIAN ARMY)

Oct 2006 to Nov 2011

Education and Training

Bachelor of Medicine & Surgery (MBBS)
 Kasturba Medical College (Mangalore, Manipal)

Post Graduate Certificate in Evidence Based Diabetes Medicine
 (PGCEBDM) Public Health Foundation of India (Delhi)

 CME Credit (Rajasthan Medical Council) EUNOIA 2017 Fortis Escorts Hospital (Jaipur, Rajasthan)

Hobbies

- Golf
- Mountaineering
- Mobility Training